罗纳石
欢迎关注微博@ UUU字幕组 获取最新熟肉信息!
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
Husky
校对
特效
presisco
压制
太空是挺不错
Space is great,
但来点地球大气层也是极好的
but nothing beats some good ol'atmosphere.
颤抖吧! 战栗吧!
The horror! The terror!
学会保护自己
Protect yourself against the menace
不受海滩市危险分子的威胁!
that threatens Beach City!
学会保护自己
Protect yourself against the menace
不受海滩市危险分子的威胁?
that threatens Beach City?
微笑先生! 来学习保护自己
Mr. Smiley, protect yourself against the menace
不受海滩市危险分子的威胁?
that threatens Beach City?
我想学习保护自己
I'll protect myself from the menace
不受海滩市危险分子的威胁
that threatens Beach City.
史蒂文! 我就知道我能相信你!
Steven! I knew I could count on you!
学习新知识!
Let's get knowledgeable!
"如何保护自己不受石头人的威胁"?
"How to Protect Yourself Against Rock People"?
啥?
What?
"外星生命在我们之中"?
"Alien entities walk among us"?
"它们向公共饮用水中投放洗脑矿物--"
"They're adding mind-controlling minerals to our water suppl--"
"它们仇恨人类"?!
"They hate men"?!
学会保护自己--
Protect yourself-against the menace that--
罗纳多! 等下! 这是什么?
Ronaldo! Wait! What is this?
这个 严格说来 是个情报杂志小手册
Well, technically,-it's an infozine pamphlet,
但是我一般管它叫 罗氏册子
but I've been calling them Ronalphlets.
那个我懂
I get that part.
我是在说里面的这些
I'm talking about all this mean stuff
关于宝石们的刻薄评论!
you're saying about the Crystal Gems!
不不不 水晶宝石们不是石头人
No, no, no.-Crystal Gems aren't rock people.
水晶宝石是石头人的敌人
Crystal Gems fight rock people.
参见我的纪录片"潮起与天塌"
See my documentary--"Rising Tides, Crashing Skies."
水晶宝石不光是石头人的敌人 我们就是石头人!
Crystal Gems don't just fight rock people. We are rock people!
还有 石头人这个称呼算是种族歧视
Also, don't say "rock people."It's offensive.
石头人明显和水晶宝石不同 你看不出来吗
Rock people are different, obviously.
最基本的讲 石头人身体中镶嵌有石头
For starters, they have rocks embedded in their bodies.
像这样?
Like this?
它们还能从泥巴维度里
But they can summon weapons
召唤武器
from the Mud Dimension.
不不 你还是没懂
No, no, you're not getting it.
它们还会改变形状
They can alter their forms.
然后就能让人类喜欢上它们!
That's how they trick humans into loving them!
嗷--
-Awwww!
等下
Wait a second.
你是个石头人?!
You're a rock person?!
我是个水晶宝石 罗纳多
I'm a Crystal Gem, Ronaldo.
你倒没把所有事都搞错
And you're not wrong about everything.
我们一直被忽视和误解
We're just ignored and misunderstood.
真幸运你是唯一一个拿了罗氏册子的!
I'm so glad you're the only one that took a Ronalphlet!
我太抱歉了!
I'm so sorry!
嘿 没关系的
Hey, it's okay.
人都会犯错的
Everyone makes mistakes.
水晶宝石们和你并没有不同
Just as long as you realize that the Crystal Gems and I
你知道这些就好了
aren't that different from you.
好 谢谢你 史蒂文
Right. Thanks, Steven.
我得回去...重新思考下
I gotta go...rethink some things.
"我要关掉这个博客"啥啥啥的
"I'm shutting down my blog,"blah blah blah,
"社交网站"啥的
"social media,"blah.
"我可能以后再也不会上网了!"
"I may never come back to the Internet!"
哇哦 伙计
Whoa, dude.
这该算是件好事
I suppose it's a good thing
至少他开始认真思考了
that he's taking time to think.
又有新帖
There's a new post.
嗯-是个视频
Hmm.-It's a video.
你好 我忠实的粉丝们
Good day, loyal followers of Keep Beach City Weird.
我今天来这里是因为
I've come to you today because I pride myself
我要为你们道出真相
in bringing you the truth
那些关于海滩市怪奇事件的
about all the weird stuff in Beach City
某些人不愿让你们知道的真相
The Man doesn't want you to know about.
但是今天 我要告诉你们这个人的真相!
But today, I need to tell you some truths about this man!
我搞混了是非黑白
I've mixed up what is right and wrong
还说了些刻薄的话语
and ended up saying some pretty mean things
针对水晶宝石们
about the Crystal Gems.
我为我的错误感到内疚
I feel terrible about my mistake
因为我比任何人都明白
because I know more than anyone what it's like
做一个没有回报的旁观者是什么感觉!
to do thankless work and to be an outsider!
所以我现在要加入水晶宝石们!
That's why I'm joining the Crystal Gems!
啥?!
What?!
史蒂文!
Steven!
罗纳多!
Ronaldo!
你猜怎么!
Guess what!
你要加入水晶宝石?
You want to join the Crystal Gems?
谢谢你的邀请!
I thought you'd never ask!
你知道吗 我一直都觉得这里有家的感觉
You know, I always felt strangely at home here.
不行 不 你不能住在这里
Unh-unh. No. You are not living here.
你更不能加入水晶宝石
And you certainly can't join the Crystal Gems.
但...
But...
你连个宝石都没有
You don't have a gem.
你身体是有机物做的
Your body is organic.
我身体也是有机物做的 我也是水晶宝石
My body's organic, and I'm a Crystal Gem.
你真打算收留他?
You're going to entertain this?
我们虽然很不同 但是我们彼此关爱和接纳
We're all different, but we love and accept each other.
这才是水晶宝石的态度
That's what Crystal Gems do.
何况现在终于
And isn't it great that someone
有人对我们的工作感兴趣了
is actually interested in what we do?
他如果成为水晶宝石
What better way to show him what we're about
就更能了解我们的工作了
than to accept him as a Crystal Gem, too?
呃....
Uhhh...
就这么做!
Let's do this!
这个嘛 他也不算是最古怪的客人了...
Well, it's not the strangest houseguest we've had.
什么时候能指派给我一个宝石身份?
So, when do I get issued my gem?
哦 其实不是--呃--
Ohhhh. It doesn't really--uh--eh--
假如你有个宝石 你希望是块什么宝石?
But if you had a gem, what would you want it to be?
这个 我心思细腻
Well, I care so much,
我想它应该在我内心深处
I think it'd be, like, deep in my heart.
或者像千万个宝石碎片
Or like a million tiny gems,
在我的血管中随血液流动
like one crushed-up gem coursing through my blood,
比如-血石!
like--like...Bloodstone!
完美! 血石就是你的宝石名了!
Perfect!-That's your Crystal Gem name.
等下! 看这个!
Wait! Check it out!
我也有个宝石武器了!
I have a gem weapon now, too!
哇! 一把剑!
Wow! A sword!
我去年在半岛漫展买的
I got it at Delmarva Con last year.
是个动漫的道具
It's a replica from the anime
叫"我的继父哪有可能是把剑"
"I Can't Believe My Stepdad Is My Sword."
用这把剑来斩断一盒牛奶
It can cut through a carton of milk
就跟切一盒黄油那么简单!
like a carton of butter!
电视上有半盒果汁
There's a half-full juice box by the TV.
喝.......
Huhhhh...
啊!
Ahhhh!
棒! 这个星星很好看哦
Nice! That star looks good on you.
谢谢
Thanks.
做任务了!
Mission time!
超棒!
Awesome!
等我把我的太刀拿来
Let me grab my katana from upstairs.
我得走楼梯了
I'm gonna take the stairs.
呃 不好意思啊 血-血罗
Uh, I'm sorry, Bloodfry.
这次你得在家里等了
You're going to have to sit this one out.
这次的任务有点危险
It's a bit dangerous.
但是史蒂文就能去啊
But Steven gets to go.
史蒂文和你不一样
Steven is different.
他已经跟我们训练了很多年了
He's been training with us for years.
别担心 血石
Don't worry, Bloodstone.
她们一开始也不让我参加任务
I didn't get to come along at first, either.
很快就可以开始训练你了
We can start your training soon.
马上回来!
Be back in a bit!
但是...我也是个水晶宝石啊
But...I'm a Crystal Gem, too.
呃...你好 血石
Um...hi, Bloodstone.
哦 你好啊史蒂文 我没注意到你在这儿
Oh. Hi, Steven. Didn't see you there.
没有我拖后腿的任务进行得怎样啊?
So...how'd the mission go without me holding you back?
呃 进行得还好
Uh, it went fine.
你知道的 跟往常一样--
You know, the usual--
打打怪物 交流下感情什么的
fighting monsters, sharing emotions.
没有我帮你 你还没受伤真是太好了
I'm glad you didn't get hurt--with me not there.
是啊
Yeah.
嗯 我要出去了
Well, I'm heading out.
你这样就出门了?
And you're going out like that?
有什么不对吗?
Uh...like what?
我就是在想 水晶宝石出门的时候
Well, I just think a real Crystal Gem
不该每时每刻都把宝石炫耀给别人看吗
would want to show off their gem, like, all the time.
要是我有宝石的话 我肯定到处炫耀的
If I had a gem, I'd show mine off.
置身于安静的森林
You are in a quiet forest.
树木是安静的 天空是安静的
The trees are quiet. The sky is quiet.
一只小兔子开始唱歌
A small rabbit begins to sing.
啊....
Ahhhh...
-啊!-我了个--
-Rahh!-What the--
血石 我知道你想训练
Bloodstone, I know you want to train,
但是现在已经是睡觉的时间了
but it's bedtime.
你竟然还会睡觉 宝石们不用睡觉的
Funny that you...sleep, when gems don't need sleep.
你为什么要睡觉?
Why is that?
我--我不知道
I--I don't know.
大概因为我是半人 我还是会累的...
Because I'm half human, I get tired and I...
哈 我还算是两个半人呢 我都不...
Huh. Well, I'm two halves human, and I'm not...
我都不困
...tired at all.
自打我成为水晶宝石那一刻起
Ever since I became a Crystal Gem,
呃...睡眠...
uh...sleeping...
我...不需要
...I don't...
不需要
do it.
那你很棒棒啊 血石
That's great, Bloodstone.
多酷的名字
What a cool name.
多酷的我
I'm so cool.
再见 康妮! 明天剑术训练的时候见!
Bye, Connie! See you tomorrow for sword training!
啊!
Aah!
她的宝石武器是把剑 对吧?
Her gem weapon's a sword, huh?
她--她完全是山寨我的设定
She totally-ripped that off from me.
啥?! 那把剑是我妈妈的!
What?! That sword belonged to my mom!
那我为什么没有你妈妈的石器?
How come I don't get your mom's gempon?
石器是"宝石武器"的简称
That's "gem"and "weapon."
这个 康妮也算是水晶宝石的一员
Well, Connie's been a part of the Crystal Gems
加入的时间比你长...
longer than you, so...
承认吧--她能加进来只是因为她是你女朋友
Admit it--She's just in because she's your girlfriend.
你在说些什么?!
What are you talking about?!
她根本都不住在这儿!
She doesn't even live here!
而我一直都在!
I'm here all the time!
看看沙发上我的印记!
Look at that quality groove I've established!
如果她算是个水晶宝石的话
If she was a real Crystal Gem,
那她该更用心一些的
she'd be a little bit more dedicated!
你在开玩笑吗?!
Are you serious?!
血石 自从你来到这儿
Bloodstone, ever since you got here,
你一直都在对我指手画脚!
all you've done is boss me around!
你有什么资格教育别人怎么成为水晶宝石?!
Who are you to tell anyone how to be a Crystal Gem?!
你就是个--就是个
You're just--You're just...
你就是个博主而已!
a guy with a blog!
你这叫爱吗?
Is that love?
你这叫接纳吗?
Is that acceptance?
也许你才没资格当水晶宝石
Maybe you're the one that isn't a Crystal Gem.
你该走了--好好反思下自己
I think you need to leave--and think about stuff.
我到底是怎么了?
What is my problem?
他只是想加入我们
He just wanted to be included.
如果我是个水晶宝石的话 我肯定不会--
If I were really a Crystal Gem, I'd never--
等一下
Wait a second.
紫晶?!
Amethyst?!
哟 我可啥也没说啊
Yo, I didn't even say anything.
血石! 咱俩得谈谈!
Bloodstone! We need to talk!
你说的不错! 水晶宝石是要有爱和接纳!
You're right! The Crystal Gems are about love and acceptance!
但是你却一直在欺凌我
But you've been acting really mean to me,
一点都不有爱
and I don't love that.
我也不会接纳这些
I don't accept that.
我不该这么讲你的
I wish I hadn't snapped at you.
我只是--觉得你加入我们
it's just---I really thought you joined
是因为你对宝石们感兴趣
because you were interested in the Crystal Gems.
但是每到事情不是以你为中心的时候 你就撒手不管了
But the second it wasn't about you, you stopped caring.
这可不是为了
This isn't the Bloodstone club
取悦你而建立的血石俱乐部
about making Bloodstone feel good.
这可是我的日常生活!
This is my whole life!
你是不是一点都不关心?!
Do you care about that or not?!
哇!
Whoa!
你的嘴炮把他弄死了!
You truthed him so hard, he died!
不!
No!
血石! 血石!
Bloodstone! Bloodstone!
他只是睡着了
He's just asleep.
一星期修仙不睡觉
Guess staying awake for a whole week
终于得到报应了
finally caught up with him.
现在应该拿石头罗怎么办
Well, what do we do with Fryrocko now?
应该通知下他父母他回来了
We should let his parent know he's back.
嘿 爹 我到家啦
Hey, Dad. I'm back.
博客 博客 博客
Blog, blog, blog.
模仿得很不错呢
That was really good!
谢谢
Thanks!
我给皮弟发个短信 让他知道罗纳多回来了
I'll...text Peedee-and let him know he's here.
你觉得他会没事吗?
You think he'll be okay?
你已经替他操心够多了
You've worried about him enough, Steven.
水晶宝石们 回去吧
Crystal Gems, let's head back.
血石!
Bloodstone!
哦 你好 史蒂文
Oh. Hey, Steven.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我已经三个星期没见你了
I haven't seen you in three weeks.
是啊 我睡了好长时间
Yeah. I took a real long nap.
然后又思考了好多
And then I did some hard thinking.
我的行为根本不像血石
I wasn't acting like Bloodstone.
我表现得像个--罗混球
I was acting like-Jerknaldo.
你接纳了我 我还是感觉像个局外人
You accepted me, but I still felt like an outsider.
我猜在局外人之中 我算是究极局外人了
I guess even amongst outsiders, I am the ultimate outsider.
我猜我罗纳多注定要独自一人
I think it's better Ronaldo Fryman work alone.
你确定?
Are you sure?
我是非常感激你想帮我们
I was really glad-you wanted to help our cause.
我仍然在啊
I still do.
哦 这是你和珍珠在握手
Oh. It's you and Pearl shaking hands.
什么时候的事?
When did that happen?
我用了修图软件的魔法
I used the magic-of photo-editing software.
嘿 这个 不管罗氏小册子了
Hey, but, uh...Ronalphlets aside,
我能问你个问题吗?
can I ask you something?
可以
Yeah.
你为什么不用你的宝石名?
Why don't you use your Gem name?
哦 我的宝石名就是我妈妈的名字
Oh. My Gem name is my mom's name.
事实上 宝石们叫我宝石名的时候
Actually, the only time Gems really call me that
一般都是要绑架或者暴打我
is if they're about to kidnap me or beat me up.
真辛苦呢 老弟
That's rough, buddy.
你想让我写进罗氏小册子里吗?
You want me to put that in the Ronalphlet?
呃...还是不要了
Ehh...maybe not.
明白
Got it.